Yes, I want you to be my man.
Keep still.
Ms. Matsu!
Hanjiro has arrived!
I'll be right out!
Who's Hanjiro?
You don't know him?
He's the star kabuki actor in Osaka!
Darling!
Mr. Hanjiro Hanai has arrived,
darling.
I am Hanjiro Hanai.
I'm Tachibana.
Sit.
Thank you.
Make yourself at home.
Allow me to pour you one.
How long will you be in Nagasaki?
The show wraps
at the end of the month.
I'm grateful
for your protection.
Well...
Inform any of my men
if you're inconvenienced.
This is such a grand New Year banquet!
Thank you.
Oh, Snowbound Barrier.
Tokuji!
You're so dashing!
What a talented geisha
you have in Nagasaki!
That's not a geisha.
It's my son, Kikuo.
Such an amateur performance
is embarrassing.
Where did the strange woman come from?
She suddenly appeared at this
border post in the middle of mountain...
Where are you from?
I'm from Shumoku,
the pleasure district.
Why are you here?
To see someone.
Who?
You, actually.
You've come to see me?
Yes, I want you to be my man.
Your son has a gift!
By the way, madam,
what is your name?
Sumizome... That's my name.
I'm so hot!
Everyone loved you!
What unflinching performances!
Before I knew it, it was over!
People would pay to see you perform!
I was worried but you did well!
I nearly had a heart attack.
Mum!
Kikuo.
Hanjiro wants to speak with you.
About what?
Just hurry.
Tokuji.
Does your back hurt?
I got used to it.
It only hurts
when a girl clings onto me!
You talked to Tatsu?
- He doesn't want to.
- Why?
He doesn't want to give you a tattoo.
He's afraid of the Boss
or your stepmum finding out.
Oh, that Tatsu is a chicken!
By the way, weren't we great?
I'm from Shumoku,
the pleasure district.
Why are you here?
To see someone.
Who?
You, actually.
Hurry!
Come this way!
We've got to hide!
You too, Tokuji!
It's an attack!
Tokuji, help me stop Kikuo!
Young master!
Get out, Boss!
Kikuo!
Keep him there.
Gongoro!
Run!
But darling!
Open the doors!
Damn it, let me go!
Let me go!
No! You'd die if I did that.
Kikuo.
Watch me.
Don't look away.
Kikuo.
You won't avenge your dad's death,
will you?
Of course not.
I wouldn't be able to go on
if you died.
I have no plan for vengeance.
I'll go...
wherever you go.
Kikuo!
What are you doing?
Keep the change.
You had a long trip from home.
Get some sleep.
Help me over there.
Arch your back!
Thank you for letting me stay,
I'm Kikuo Tachibana.
I appreciate your kindness.
Your mother wanted you
to have an honest occupation.
What do you want?
I'll respect her wishes.
The Tachibana family is a big deal,
isn't it?
Yes, ma'am, but they're dissolving.
Are you alone?
The A Bomb disease
killed my real mum, uncle and aunt.
There's no one else I can depend on.
He'll live and train with us?
That's what Master Hanai wants.
You arrived so early.
You must be hungry.
Let's have lunch.
Follow me.
Help me, Sei.
Where are you?
We're here.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, ma'am.
- Hello.
- Good afternoon.
- Hello, ma'am.
Hey, don't touch!
Sorry! Let's get going.
- Ma'am.
- Keep it up!
Let's have a good show.
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
- Hello.
Hey, Gen.
- Ma'am.
- Look after the boy.
Excuse me.
Hey, kid!
You're in the way, kid.
You'll train him to be a kabuki actor?
He's the son of a yakuza!
Look after him.
But it's so sudden!
He's not a lost puppy.
I still remember him
playing Sumizome.
- He's an amateur.
- Pardon me.
Thank you for taking me in.
You can take it easy.
That's Shunsuke, our son.
You're the same age.
Go to school together.
No, thanks.
Your stage name is...
Toichiro Hanai.
Number one man of the east.
That suits him!
I'm Hanya, Half a guy.
Why's that?
You'll be Hanjiro the Third
and that's better!
But I don't know, dear...
How can I mother such a big boy?
I can't imagine him
living with us for years.
We can't send him
back to Nagasaki now.
The kid's brave.
You avenged your father, right?
I tried... and failed.
It requires guts.
Step back.
You're pushing my patience!
Step out further!
Fist here.
Twist this hand inward!
Let your bones memorise the pose.
Holding a pose is hard, right?
Let your bones remember
the best position.
Engage your blades...
Got it?
There are no short cuts to learning!
Keep it up!
Again.
Ready, do it!
You're pushing my patience!
I told you many times!
You call yourself an actor?
Watch your shoulder blades.
Put them together!
Keep your hand up!
It hurts!
Is he always so strict?
Worse! With two teachers in the house,
the boy has no time to sleep.
Put them together!
Good. Open your legs wider!
And here!
Move! You'll make that tattoo
cry in shame!
Ouch!
Again.
Kikuo?
Why didn't you come to the bar, Kikuo?
You'll catch a cold.
Come inside.
I missed you so much.
I'm sorry I haven't spent
any time with you, Harue.
I saw you train.
You did?
Mr. Hanai is an amazing teacher.
When I do like he says,
it changes my form.
But it's too much...
But I like it.
I don't even need sleep.
It's unnecessary to
- favour your master!
- If you do
you might hurt yourself!
Then he blocks him with
both his arms out.
It was off. Let's do it again.
The flowers
in the stream are deep purple
Shunsuke.
Watch him.
Yes.
Dance by yourself.
Is that an owl?
It's an eagle owl.
They always return favours.
They'll bring you snakes and mice.
No thanks, that's creepy.
I can get you some.
Don't make me laugh...
A snake or a mouse?
I hate both of them!
How's Kikuo?
He absorbs everything like a sponge.
He's so bottomless, it's scary.
An empty vessel.
A natural born onnagata.
Our heir should work harder
for his position.
Would it be interesting
to pair them up as onnagata?
You think so, too?
Our son will train
more seriously with Kikuo.
Sometimes he's too laid-back...
I'm tired. I'm off to bed.
It was a long day.
Another hard day tomorrow.
Hurry up!
We'll go to the station?
Yes, Gen is waiting with our luggage.
Ready?
Here goes!
Will you really take me to Gion?
Yes! And I'll show you
how things are done.
Are geisha girls pretty?
They smell nice.
So you'll be
my dad's apprentice?
There's talk of it...
That's a privilege.
You'll get special treatment!
You might land a big part.
Not for many years.
No, it won't be long.
Twirl once, twirl twice,
twirl three times...
But you won!
One for you.
Thank you.
Hey, Shunsuke.
You drunk it up!
Is this your first visit
to a geisha house, Toichiro?
No!
I see.
I've got to pee!
I guess Nagasaki is much warmer.
Does it snow at all?
Snow...
Hardly ever.
I've decided...
I'll go with you all the way.
What do you mean?
I'm saying I'll bet my life on you,
Toichiro.
But we just met.
I don't want to waste time.
Are you serious?
I'm a woman who sticks to her word.
I have a hunch that you're destined
to be a great actor.
I'm not so audacious
to ask you to marry me.
I want to be your mistress,
even if I'm Number 3.
Okay?
It's too soon.
It isn't. Before you know it
I'll be an old woman.
Toichiro.
You'll be
the best kabuki actor in Japan.
Promise me.
Do you have a minute, Mangiku?
It's Hanjiro.
Hi, Mr. Tanba-ya.
My son and an apprentice
want to greet you.
Shunsuke, is that you?
It's been so long.
How you've grown!
He's 16.
Kikuo.
Help yourself.
Thank you, sir.
This boy is our apprentice.
He is Kikuo Tachibana.
They'll learn a lot from your performance
in Heron Maiden.
It's an honour.
Thank you.
Let's go.
- Excuse us.
Kikuo, is it?
Hold on...
I must say...
What a beautiful face.
I see what Mr. Tanba-ya saw in you.
But be careful.
It might get in the way of your art.
Your beautiful face
might consume you.
It's kind of surreal.
He's a monster.
Yes but he's a beautiful monster.
A living national treasure.
So he should be.
Hi there, Gen!
Get some ice water.
It's ready.
How many bars?
I don't know! I woke up
on the floor of a strange bar.
It was a shock!
You party too much.
We're on soon.
I've got to get ready...
Hurry up!
Are you ready?
Not yet, not yet...
Hey! You're getting me wet!
Thank you for coming again!
How are you, President Umeki?
Let me take your shoes.
Thank you for coming.
I'm here on a business trip.
Great, you're upstairs.
Let's speak later.
I feel sick...
There they are!
Gorgeous kimono!
Excellent!
We missed the beat
when we look at each other.
When we put down the hats?
Yes, let's go over it.
Okay.
That's good.
Do it once more.
If I knew you'd come, sir...
Don't be so formal!
Shunsuke and Kikuo!
Someone's here to see you.
I saw your Wisteria Maiden.
It was impressive!
I'm very lucky to have seen it.
Who is he?
The president of
Mitsutomo Corporation.
Thank you, sir.
There you are!
Hanya and Toichiro!
Aren't they amazing, Takeno?
I don't know, sir.
You don't understand
the art of kabuki.
They should perform
at Miyako-za Theater.
It's generous but
they lack experience for that venue.
I know it's a gamble.
Future stars or
failure of the century!
Temple Maiden has the right energy
for young stars!
It's too soon, sir.
They're not ready for that...
- They'll be fine.
- But, sir...!
The new stars' debut
at Miyako-za!
Not so fast, sir...
Miyako-za!
Did you hear that, Gen?
I certainly did.
Congratulations!
What's with you?
Did you smirk?
Kabuki is a family trade.
But you're an outsider.
Everything is good now
but your downfall will come.
Hey!
Say that again.
It might be all good now
but your downfall will come.
Cocky bastard!
You punk!
I'll rip you apart!
Sirs.
Another bouquet.
I'll take it.
How's it going?
I'm shaking...
Get it together.
- Shunsuke.
- Yes?
You were born into
a family of actors.
So your family blood
will always protect you.
Kikuo.
Have you taken a day off
from practice in seven years?
No, you haven't.
If you forget a move,
your body will remember.
Off you go.
Look at you...
You're beautiful...
See you.
Shunsuke.
Come here.
What?
Ouch, what the--!
Come on, my turn.
Come on.
Ready?
That hurt!
Off we go, Kikuo.
Meet you on the runway.
I'll raise you.
How am I doing?
So so.
I'll watch you.
Are you ready?
Cheers!
The Toichiro Hanya Duo is a hit!
Girls line up for tickets
and the line extends to Gojo Bridge.
Yeah, thank you.
You're the To-Han Duo!
I saw you on TV!
Come see us
at the Naniwa-za Theater next month.
How was it when you finished
your first show?
I've been on stage
since I was a toddler.
So it was nothing.
And Toichiro?
It was scenery
I'd never seen before...
Why is it To-Han Duo?
Why's his name come first?
- It sounds better.
- It sucks!
It should be Han-To!
To-Han is better.
No! I should come first!
Who cares?
I do!
Hi, Kikuo.
Harue!
- Listen to this!
- What?
This man here says nothing interesting
in interviews.
It's all "Yes, thank you so much."
You don't give me a chance to speak!
Kikuo is all about the performance.
Actors should entertain
on and off stage!
We should take out loans
and host parties!
We need patrons, so be loveable.
You're loveable, right?
I'm more loveable!
Aren't I?
You are!
I'm the heir!
Marry me.
You don't want to?
You're at a crossroad
in your career, Kikuo.
You know what?
I'll work hard so I can be
your Number One patron.
I'll buy you a Persian carpet.
I'll work even more
so that I can build you a theater.
You'll be the main attraction.
Everyone in the audience
will be infatuated with you.
Pardon me.
Gen!
Is Dad OK?
No. I mean he's OK but...
He was on his way home.
It was a huge accident!
I thought I'd have a heart attack.
The car turned and
a truck hit it with a bang!
Luckily, he'll be OK in a month.
Right.
How about his show?
It begins in five days.
There's no understudy.
Shunsuke, listen.
Prepare for the unexpected.
The heir is the only one
who could do it.
Well, yeah...
It's been decided.
Hello, Mr. Umeki.
You've memorised
his lines and moves?
Yes, I watched
Dad practice every day.
This is a huge break!
You'll be in the headlines.
It's not decided yet.
But...
Who decided?
You heard me.
This isn't the time to joke around.
Don't make me repeat myself.
Kikuo is replacing me.
But he's an apprentice!
- Shunsuke's your son!
- It's decided!
But dear...
That's not how it's supposed to be.
It makes no sense!
He'll replace
Hanjiro Hanai the Second
and play the heroine
in Love Suicide?
How can I explain this
to the patrons?
Tell them what you want.
Shunsuke!
Just like a thief...
You broke in
and stole my belongings.
You petty thief.
I'm going to get you.
I'm not bluffing!
I guess that would be
more dramatic...
Hanjiro the Second
favours an apprentice over his son.
Nothing that I say
will change that fact.
Do you think I'm capable
of standing in for your father?
I guess no one is exactly up to it.
Shunsuke!
Where are you going?
For a walk.
Without evidence,
Tokubei won't be able to defend himself.
His only chance
of vindication is to kill himself.
Does he have the resolve to die--
Wrong!
Disgusting!
Does he have the resolve--
Again!
Does he have the resolve to die--
You idiot!
You don't sound like you're resolved
to die with your lover!
Again!
Does he have the resolve to die--
Without evidence, Tokubei won't be
able to defend himself.
His only chance
of vindication is to kill himself.
The next ring of the bell is
the last one we'll hear
on this earth...
Such a tasteless delivery.
You'll die at the next bell.
You fear death but
you're also happy to die with your lover.
I'm not feeling that from you!
Live like Ohatsu to know
how to die like her!
The next ring of the bell is
the last one we'll hear
on this earth.
Amazing! It's unbelievable
that he's never played the part.
An apprentice might take over
the House of Tanba-ya.
Shunsuke?
What are you doing?
Avoiding the rain.
Come in.
No, I'm going.
See you.
Kikuo, it's me.
What's wrong?
It's almost time
but I can't stop shaking.
Look at me.
Promise not to get mad.
What I crave now
is your blood, Shunsuke.
I don't have it to protect me.
I wish I could drink
a cup of your blood.
Come on, you have a gift.
You'll be fine.
You're OK.
- I'm fine.
- You are.
It's all because of that scheming man.
He tricked Tokubei
into this inescapable mess.
Without evidence,
Tokubei won't be able to defend himself.
His only chance
of vindication is to kill himself.
Does he have the resolve to die?
That's what I want his word on.
I'm sure
he has the resolve.
What good would come
from him living like this?
Death will wash away
the shame inflicted on him.
What are you talking about, Ohatsu?
Tokubei wouldn't kill himself.
If he ever did kill himself
depend on me, Kuheiji,
I will be your lover.
I've always known that you love me.
You'll be my lover, will you?
That's awfully generous of you.
If you were in a relationship with me
you'd realise that
I'd have to kill you, too?
How would I live a minute longer
without Tokubei?
He has the resolve to die.
I have the resolve
to die with him, too!
Shunsuke...
Shunsuke?
I'm not running...
I'm not running!
I know.
I...
I want to be a real actor.
Not a pretend one.
Come on!
You were great.
You really were!
I found a spaceman.
Have you been good?
Your mum's working hard.
You hardly come, Dad.
- You sure?
- I almost forgot who you are.
When will you visit us again?
I don't know...
Ayano.
Let's eat something.
How about that?
You're asking God for a lot.
I was making a deal
with the devil, not with God.
Is the devil here?
Sure!
What kind of deal?
I asked him to
make me a better kabuki actor.
The best one in the whole of Japan.
I'd give him
everything I own for that.
What did Mr. Devil say?
He said, "Okay. It's a deal."
Come on, Ayano.
There are steps here.
Listen, Kikuo.
I've been thinking.
I can't see well
but while I have some vision
I want to bloom once more.
So I succeed to the name of
Byakko Hanai, and
you can take my name,
Hanjiro Hanai the Third.
What about Shunsuke?
He's been gone for eight years.
If he'd wanted it
he'd have returned.
Turn it down, Kikuo.
Shunsuke only has the name,
Hanjiro, to come back for.
It has the power
to change things for him.
It's so important
for your son but you'd give it away?
He left because he couldn't take it.
Have you forgotten his reason?
You actors...!
You're such greedy creatures!
You're half blind from diabetes.
But you have to ruin your son's life
for the prestigious name of Byakko.
Ma'am...
And you!
You filthy thief,
you take away everything from Shunsuke.
And Shunsuke...
He couldn't admit defeat.
He just ran...
He's shameless!
Ayano!
Dad!
Dad?
- Dad!
- Ayano!
You'd better watch out.
Dad...
Let's go.
Kikuo.
We need to talk before
I hand over the House of Tanba-ya.
Yes, Master?
In the kabuki world
you're nobody if your father
isn't a kabuki actor.
All you have to fight detractors
is the art of kabuki.
In its true form,
it's stronger than swords and guns.
Master the art of kabuki.
That's your sweet revenge.
Okay?
Yes.
Promise me.
Thank you for coming all this way.
Thank you for coming.
We're here.
There's a step.
The entrance.
Thank you for waiting.
Hello.
Sorry for the wait.
Thank you.
Right here.
East to west!
Everyone from the east to the west!
Excuse us for addressing you
from a position
that is higher than yours.
With Mitsutomo Corporation's
encouragement
and endorsement from all involved
Hanjiro will be
Byakko Hanai the Fourth
and Toichiro will be
Hanjiro the Third.
Each will hereby succeed
the honourable names before you.
As announced by Mr. Izumi-ya just now
I will succeed the honourable name
of my master Hanjiro
to become Hanjiro Hanai the Third.
Hanjiro the Third!
When I was fifteen years old
I was an orphan when my master
took me under his wing.
I've been on a journey
of strict training since then.
But it was all beautiful
and exciting to my eyes and ears.
The years passed
in an instance, like a dream.
To return the favour and
to make the House of Tanba-ya proud
I will dedicate my life
to being an accomplished performer.
I appreciate your continuing support
as I work to improve
with the deepest gratitude
from my heart.
Master?
Sir!
Master!
The curtain!
Close it!
Close the curtain now!
Don't close the curtain!
This is my stage!
- Master.
- Open it!
Open the curtain!
Open it please!
Ambulance!
Call an ambulance!
Master...
Shunsuke.
Shunsuke...
Sir!
Carry him out!
Ready?
Don't let him go.
Are you okay?
Dear!
Oh, no...!
Shunsuke...
No, no! Don't go, dear!
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
I will hold a grudge
against you forever.
Hanjiro the Third.
Where's Shunsuke?
Kikuo...
Thanks for everything you've done.
I'm truly...
grateful.
What actor takes such a long break?
I'm glad you're alive.
Listen.
I'd appreciate it
if you saw Harue, too.
We have a child.
Was it hard for you too,
as his wife?
We survived those 10 years
thanks to the generosity of others.
We were given work
in hotels as kitchenhands...
And Shunsuke performed
at hotel banquets
or in travelling troupes...
Every day I tried to
ignite something in the audience.
I could see it in their eyes.
Did you think
about going back to kabuki?
I'm just a pathetic loser
who ran from it.
I was accustomed to
people running to help if I cried.
I wasn't even there for
my father's name succession ceremony.
I deserve to be called
the worst son in the world.
Why was I born as heir
to the House of Tanba-ya?
As the son of a kabuki actor?
I've been looking for answers...
He's a terrible actor!
He's horrendous!
He's just so hopeless.
Hanjiro the Third.
It's crowded!
Look who's here!
Shunsuke's been cast already.
He acted during those 10 years
but nothing major like this!
But if Mangiku thinks he's up to it,
he must be.
The House of Tanba-ya
can be so heartless...
You've been taking care
of your master's debts.
Give them to Shunsuke.
I look virtuous if
I treat his debts as my own.
But you're in arrears
and they only give you walk-on roles.
You haven't starred in years.
I'm so pathetic...
They abandoned you,
when your master died.
In their eyes, you snatched
the Hanjiro name from the family.
I guess it's too late
to return it...
I better go.
Elbow!
You...
Your mindset is wrong,
that's why your performance is rough.
You need to be a young woman.
A young woman wouldn't dare
move like that.
Right.
Go.
You.
You hate kabuki with a passion,
don't you?
It's fine if you do.
You still go on stage.
Why?
Because I guess
that's what makes us actors.
Again.
Why?
Mr. Fujimi-ya...
What is it?
Are you doing the ninth act of
47 Ronin in October?
That's right.
Have you already cast the heroine?
You want to do it?
A heroine with a yakuza tattoo
on her back sounds interesting!
Listen.
When you're caught up in a scandal,
just stay low.
Everyone will soon
forget about it.
Actors don't have
to pretend to be saints.
You know that, right?
Give me the silk wig cap.
Uncle Kikuo!
I was looking for you.
I thought you'd left.
- You here to see Dad?
- No.
Will you come to my mother's
birthday party?
Sure.
Really?
It'll be great!
It's a promise.
I'll get back to you.
See you!
Hi, Dad!
Hey, Akiko!
Your Highness!
The Heike Clan's demise is imminent.
I will die and
wait for you to join me.
So I can show you the way to heaven.
Now!
We'll say goodbye!
Dad, please don't. Dad!
Stay back!
You...
What have you done to my daughter?
Dad, don't!
Stay away, Akiko!
Did you think
that I wouldn't find out?
You're scum!
I can see it in your eyes.
Uncle Kikuo...
I'm not your uncle.
You know that all he wants
is my backing!
He doesn't care a bit about you!
You're wrong!
Why can't you see that?
Calm down!
I'll be...
I'll be your wife, Kikuo.
If you want to be with him,
get the hell out of my house!
I have resolve, too.
I'll leave!
Can you get up?
About Kikuo...
Do you think kabuki
will let him come back?
I've disgraced
the House of Tanba-ya...
Gen.
Yes.
Hi, Kazutoyo! Is it yummy?
You ate a lot!
You're heir to the House of Tanba-ya!
Why don't we practice some,
Kazutoyo?
Kikuo!
Kikuo, wait!
I'm sorry.
It's for Kazutoyo's sake...
Family blood is everything, isn't it?
Forget the art of kabuki,
it's about whose son you are.
It'd be dramatic if I meant it.
I'll make sure you'll get to act.
We'll be the Han-Han Duo.
Is that a joke? Who needs the help
of a loser who ran off?
Don't throw me a bone
like a privileged kid!
You're guilty of some dirty tricks.
What?
You tricked Akiko
so you could land a role!
Did you really do that?
You son-of-a-bitch!
Stop it!
Sorry...
Sorry, Kikuo.
Are you okay? I'm sorry...
- Let me go.
- Sorry!
Give me a break...
Here goes.
The Agency for Cultural Affairs
gave out awards to newcomers.
Hanya Hanai, the kabuki actor, gave
a speech on behalf of the recipients.
I owe this honour
to my father, Byakko Hanai and
supporters of the House of Tanba-ya.
I feel that
I'm still learning my way.
To be an accomplished actor
that my father was
I persist in the strict training
Mangiku gives me.
But I'm nowhere near my father.
Not only am I pleased
to get an award, it motivates me.
I'm forever an apprentice
and I'll devote my heart and soul
to the art of kabuki.
I'll get cigarettes.
Sir!
To your seat please.
What are you doing, you idiot!
Sorry about this!
Have some water.
Look, there she is!
I don't want to...
Go get laid.
What the hell?
He's a man.
She's pretty!
What's the idea?
Leave that alone!
How do you do it?
- Like this?
- Let go of it.
- Give it back.
- Come on, show me.
- Stop it.
Show me.
I said stop!
Leave him alone!
You asshole!
You're creepy!
Are you a woman?
What the hell?
You're a fake!
Let's stop this...
What are you looking at?
Yeah, what?
What was I looking at?
Hanjiro.
Harjiro the Third!
Looking good.
Do you feel like
coming back to kabuki?
Mangiku wants to see you.
That old woman--
I mean the old man...
He's over 90!
It's been three years since he retired.
Why now?
I guess he finally approves of you.
It's sad.
He's a living national treasure!
He'll leave nothing
except his art when he dies.
It's Kikuo.
I'll let myself in.
Look around...
There's nothing beautiful in here,
is there?
Somehow
I feel relieved.
It's like someone told me
that I don't have to try anymore.
You...
Where have you been?
Dance for me.
I know you're ready.
You're heaving, Kikuo.
Shut up, so are you!
What's wrong, Shunsuke?
Bring out some drapes!
Can you get up?
Hey, Kikuo!
You came.
It's your leg?
Here.
It's gangrene.
From diabetes.
It needs to be amputated below the knee.
It looked like a sprain...
Yeah, so I didn't do
anything about it.
Do you think he should try
another hospital?
Maybe America has
more advanced treatment.
The doctor said that
there's no other option.
Do you know what it means
to amputate your leg?
Of course I do!
What roles need an actor
with one leg?
No... No...
You can't do that...
It has to be done now
or I'll lose
more than half a leg.
Shunsuke...
Stop.
Can't you do it more mindfully?
Show me the spin.
Stop!
Mind your head. Look up.
Come down from here.
Good. Do it again.
- Good.
- Hey!
Can you leave us, Kazutoyo?
Sure.
Just a second.
Thank you very much.
Good work.
Sit here.
How's the prosthesis?
As you can see...
It'll never be how it was before.
How's Kazutoyo doing?
As you can see.
So he's not cut out for onnagata?
I don't know what he's made for.
Basketball.
He could get injured
but he refuses to quit.
We ran home
to practice after school!
If we were late, Dad hit us.
With a stick.
That was crazy.
Listen...
I want to be on stage again.
Don't push yourself.
Haste makes waste.
You think so?
Gangrene in this leg
would mean amputation or death.
I want to...
be the heroine in Love Suicide.
I'm not being competitive!
It's only because
that play made me who I am.
Then I'll play the male role.
Really?
Really.
Thank you.
His only chance
of vindication is to kill himself.
Does he have the resolve to die?
That's what I want his word on.
I'm sure
he has the resolve.
What good would come
from him living like this?
Death will wash away
the shame inflicted on him.
How would I live
a minute longer without Tokubei?
No matter what
he has the resolve to die.
I have the resolve
to die with him, too!
You know.
I only have one leg.
But I don't want that
to be the attraction.
They'll come to see this leg.
I want to perform as I am.
I'll play Ohatsu as only I can.
Something's always
watching us from up there.
What is it?
Are you okay?
Master.
You should stop here.
We'll finish it.
Right?
Damn right.
Who do you think I am?
All this talk is
endless and in vain.
Kill me now. Right now!
Kill me now please!
Now!
Yes, I'm going to do it now!
I couldn't be so brave!
Call an ambulance.
Let's go...
Get up, Shunsuke.
You have to...
Get up or you'll be replaced.
16 years after Hanya Hanai died
he posthumously succeeded
the name, Byakko.
And the show opens today
to pay tribute to his life.
This year, 16 years
since you lost your soulmate
you became
a living national treasure.
And your first show
after that honour is Heron Maiden
which is the act that defines you,
Hanjiro the Third.
You're one of the
youngest recipients of that honour.
What more could you want?
You've been in the spotlight
throughout your career.
Can you share your thoughts with us?
I wouldn't be here
if not for everyone.
I have nothing but gratitude.
You perfected the art of onnagata.
Where will you go from here?
There's something I've been trying
to find all these years.
Scenery... that's what it is.
Scenery?
Like what?
I can't describe it well.
May I take some photos?
Come this way.
Could you look this way?
Let me fix your clothes...
Do you remember
a woman called Fujikoma?
A geisha from Gion.
Of course I do...
Ayano.
I've never regarded you
as my father.
To stay on the stage
you hurt many people
and made them cry.
To climb to where you are
how many people did you sacrifice?
You owe this to Mr. Devil.
But...
You know what?
Every time I saw you perform onstage
it was like a New Year celebration.
It's transformative.
"Drop everything
and enter my world."
Like you're inviting me in.
Like you're taking me
somewhere I've never been.
That's how I felt.
And I clapped at the end.
Dad...
It happened.
You became the best kabuki actor in Japan.
How beautiful...
Original Novel by Shuichi Yoshida
Screenplay by Satoko Okudera
Cinematography by Sofian El Fani
Art Direction by Yohei Taneda